20,000 Days on Earth is a documentary, drama,
music film directed by Jane Pollard.
A semi-fictionalized documentary about a day in the life of
Australian musician Nick Cave's persona.
Self, played by Nick Cave.
Self, played by Warren Ellis.
Self, played by Blixa Bargeld.
Self, played by Susie Bick.
Self, played by Arthur Cave.
Self, played by Earl Cave.
20,000 Days on Earth is a 2014 British musical documentary
drama film
co-written and directed by Iain Forsyth and Jane Pollard.
Nick Cave also co-wrote the script with Forsyth and Pollard.
The film premiered in-competition in the World Cinema Documentary
Competition at 2014 Sundance Film Festival on 20 January 2014.
It won two Awards at the festival.
After its premiere at Sundance Film Festival, Drafthouse
Films acquired distribution rights of the film.
The film released on 17 September 2014 in United States.
The film explores themes of docudrama, woman director, part fiction.
The tone is emotional.